ISAAC SHEPARD

SOFTWARE ENGINEER B.S. MATHEMATICS - COMPUTER SCIENCE MAJOR UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, SAN DIEGO

(858)-357-6167 | ishepard@ucsd.edu | in linkedin.com/in/isaacshepard77 | 🔽 github.com/shepardi | My Portfolio

Summary

Software Engineer with experience in web applications using Javascript and Python frameworks and libraries.

Web Developer Experience in building React applications scaled for enterprise-level needs.

Skills

Programming C/C++ · Python · NodeJS · Dart

Full-Stack HTML5 · CSS3/SASS · Javascript · Express · React · Redux · MongoDB · PostgreSQL · Flutter

Dev Tools Jest ' Jenkins ' Postman ' GraphQL ' Github ' Docker ' Kubernetes

Work Experience

Frontend Developer May, 2021 - Present

Qualcomm - | React ' Typescript ' Redux ' Jenkins ' Docker ' Kubernetes

Develop and Design Web application for Internal Tools

- > Used Agile development process with a cross-functional team to build an internal tooling software to boost Qualcomm's product quality.
- > Structured application to scale for enterprise level systems, allowing the application to scale for large volumes of users.

Software Engineer (Mobile)

November, 2020 - April 2021

Vytality Health - | Flutter ' Dart ' Firebase ' GraphQL

Develop the company's application focusing on UI features.

- > Refactored the company's API to prevent future development errors for newer upcoming versions of our app.
- Fixed buggy UI features to complete the company's beta app.

Full Stack Developer Intern

April, 2020 - August, 2020

General Assembly - | MongoDB · ReactJS · NodeJS · Express · Python · Django

Built web applications using Javascript and Python with MVC Frameworks

- Developed back-end REST APIs to communicate with the frontend UI.
- > Refactored web applications into ReactJS allowing for faster rendering and future feature implementation

Unity VR Game Developer

January, 2017 - March, 2018

Triton XR - | C#' Unity3D ' GoogleVR

Leveraged the Unity3D system, C# scripting, and GoogleVR to build a mobile virtual reality game Lucid Dreaming.

- > Followed an Agile workflow and GIT version control (Github) for more efficient productivity on individual features.
- Built character and environment animations for better user experience using C# scripting

Technical Projects _____

July, 2020 - August, 2020

Albion Online Hub | 🕎 github link

WEB APPLICATION - | MongoDB ' ReactJS ' NodeJS ' Express ' D3.js |

[Albion Online Hub is a web application made for the MMORPG game Albion Online. Uses the game's API to get a JSON payload for app features.]

Leveraged MERN web stack and github workflow to build a responsive web application following the MVC design pattern

- Integrated the game's external API in order to synchronize data for market and events features using jQuery and D3.js.
- Handled user authentication authorization using OAuth with MongoDB and Express framework.
- Refactored main project branch into a React application and incorporated TDD with Jest/Enzyme testing.

Education